TRUPHENA WANJIRU GIKAARA

P.O. Box 1744 – 00100 Nairobi, Kenya

Tel.: +254 724 383 078, E-mail: tgikaara@gmail.com

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Nationality Kenyan
Marital status Married
Age 34 years
Religion Christian

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Dedicated and passionate trainer of food business operators from farm to the table for over 3 years. Accomplished implementer of the international management standards (ISO) in various food industries. A FSSC 22000 Lead auditor with exceptional relationship building and communication skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

1. SGS Academy Kenya - 2018 to current

Part-time trainer

- Carrying out trainings on Food Safety and Quality Management systems (ISO 22000:2018, HACCP, GMPs, GAP) and ISO 9001:2015
 - o Bio-Medica Laboratories on implementation of HACCP
 - o Geonet Technologies Ltd on ISO 9001:2015
 - o I choose Life-Africa (Farmers) on food safety awareness and practices
 - o Intercontinental Hotel on implementation of ISO 22000:2018
- Supervise maintenance of the management systems through scheduled audits.
 - o Agricultural Development of Kenya (ADC) on ISO 9001:2015
 - Athi Water and Services Board on ISO 9001:2015
 - o Safepak ltd on FSSC 22000: 2005
 - o Legorn Feeds Ltd and Jubilee Feeds Industries Ltd on Kenya Standard 2543:2014

2. Food Safety International- 2016 to date

Part-time trainer

- Carrying out trainings on Food Safety (HACCP, GMPs, GAP) to,
 - Mastermind Kenya
 - Delmont Limited

- o Global Alliance for Improved Nutrition (GAIN) Kenya (on FBOs)
- Conducting Food safety audits to our clients.
 - o Happy Cow company
 - Proctor and Allan Ltd
 - Insta Foods (EPZ)
 - o Equatorial Nuts Company

3. Safepak Limited April 2012 to June 2016

Factory Manager

- Carrying out Internal Quality Systems Audits at planned intervals, supplier audits and link between the organization and SGS (the certification body)
- Implementation of ISO 9001:2015, FSSC 22000, PAS 96:2014, OSHAS 18001:2007 &
 KS EAS 39: 2000
- Departmental documents development, control, and review as per the Management systems
- Conducting Internal Quality Systems Audits at planned intervals, supplier audits and link between the organization and SGS (the certification body)
- Carrying out departmental trainings and evaluation of the effectiveness of the training through staff involvement for breakthrough change and innovation.

EDUCATION

- The University of Nairobi 2018 MSc., Food Safety and Quality
- Kenyatta University 2009 BSc Biochemistry 2nd Class honors Upper Division
- Kenya College of Accountancy 2007 Diploma Information Management Systems IMIS-UK
- Nyandarua High School 2003 KCSE B+
- Kahutha Primary School 1999 KCPE 557/700

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

- SGS Kenya, 2015 Lead Auditor FSSC 22000:2005
- National Quality Institute (NQI- KEBS), 2015 QMS Internal auditing ISO 19011: 2002
- NQI-KEBS, 2015 QMS Implementation ISO 9001: 2015
- SGS Kenya, 2015 Occupation Health & Safety Management Systems OSHAS 18001:
 2007

REFEREES

1. James Njoroge Kihunyu

Quality assurance Manager

Milly Glass Ltd

P.O Box 80180 Mombasa

+254 722 125 449

jameskihunyu@yahoo.com

2. Dr. George Ooko Abong'

Senior Lecturer

University of Nairobi

College of Agriculture and Veterinary Studies

+254 735 508 558

georkoyo@yahoo.com

3. Dr. Catherin Nkirote Kunyanga

Senior Lecturer

University of Nairobi

College of Agriculture and Veterinary Studies

+254 722 873 357

Ckunyanga@uonbi.ac.ke